Dr. Sunil Kumar Jangir

I. RESUME SUMMARY

CONTACT INFORMATION

Ward no.8 new, Near Trimurti Mandir, Suratgarh, Distt. Sri Ganganagar

(M):09602538312, 09251039749 Email: sunil.jangir07@gmail.com Google Scholar : https://bit.ly/2HrDZaf GitHub: https://github.com/suniljangir

Website: drsuniljangir.in

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

Degree	Subjects	Board / University	School/Institute	Year	Percentage
Ph.D.	Computer Science & Engineering	JECRC University, Jaipur	School of Engineering	2014 - 2018	Awarded in 2018
M.Tech.	Software Engineering	Suresh Gyan Vihar University, Jaipur	Gyan Vihar School of Engineering & Technology, Jaipur	2010 - 2012	8.9 CGPA (Gold Medalist)
B. E.	Information Technology	University of Rajasthan, Jaipur	Jaipur Engineering College, Kukas, Jaipur	2005 - 2009	72.63% HONS.
XII	PCM	Board of Sec. Education,Rajasthan	T.C.A. Sr. Sec. School,Suratgarh	2005	70.63%
X	General Subjects	Board of Sec. Education,Rajasthan	T.C.A. Sr. Sec. School,Suratgarh	2003	85%

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Duration	Institute /	Designation	Job Profile
	Organization		
June 2019-Till	MODY University of Science & Technology,	Assistant Professor (Senior)	Involve in study material development & research.
Nov 2009 – June 2019	Jaipur Engineering College & Research Centre, Jaipur	Associate Professor, Head- Department of Information Technology	Involve in Research, Innovation in Active Teaching learning, Incubation ,ACM,CSI-Student Branch Coordinator
July 2009 – Oct. 2009	RMG,Info Service,Gurgaon	Software Trainee	Developer (Asp.Net,C#)

PUBLICATIONS

International Journal	National Journal	International Conferences	National Conferences
06	Nil	10	08

Conferences /Workshops/International Certification Training Programs Attended/Organized

Conference /Workshops Attended		International Certification Training Programs	
International	National	Attended	Organized
6	10	5	8

II. DETAILED RESUME

PROFESSIONAL TRAITS

An Energetic, dedicated person with good communication and leadership qualities to motivate people to achieve organizational objectives.

PROFESSIONAL SYNOPSIS

Total Experience: 10Yrs 9 Months

Academic Experience: 10Yrs & 05 Months. (Nov. 2009 – Till Date)

MODY University of Science & Technology: (June 2019 – Till Date)

Full time faculty in the Department of Computer Science & Engineering (Accredited by ABET), School of Engineering & Technology, Mody University of Science & Technology, Lakshmangarh, Dist. Sikar Rajasthan – India, Affiliated to UGC and approved by AICTE, New Delhi.

Jaipur Engineering College & Research Centre: (Nov. 2009 – June 2014)

Full time faculty in the Department of Information Technology, Jaipur Engineering College & Research Centre, Jaipur, Rajasthan – India, Affiliated to Rajasthan Technical University and approved by AICTE, New Delhi.

Industrial Experience: 04 Months Software Trainee (july2009 –Oct.2009)

Project titile: "Gurgaon On call"

A search engine developed for Gurgaon which provides e-media solutions to the users and Business Associates at RMG Info Services Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon.

PUBLICATIONS

International Journal:

- Sunil Kumar Jangir, Naveen Hemrajani, "A Comprehensive Review and performance evaluation of detection Techniques of Black hole Attack in MANET", Published in Journal of Computer Science (JCS) 13 (10): 537.547, DOI: 10.3844/jcssp.2017.537.547
- Sunil Kumar Jangir, Naveen Hemrajani, "Collusion BW Hole Attack" Published in "International Journal of Advanced Research in Computer Science" Volume 8, No. 9, November-December 2017, ISSN No:: 0976-5697, DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.26483/ijarcs.v8i9.5054
- Sunil Kumar Jangir, Naveen Hemrajani, "A Comprehensive Review and Performance Evaluation of Reactive and Proactive Protocols under Routing Attacks in MANET" Published in "International Journal of Emerging Technology and Advanced Engineering" Volume 7, Issue 10, October 2017, ISSN No:: 2250–2459
- Sunil Kumar Jangir, Neha Gupta, Shreya Agrawal, "Evolution and Melioration Of Software Management Processes" Published in "International Journal of Software Engineering and Applications(IJSEA)" Vol.3, No.1, January 2012, Page No. 61-83, ISSN No:: 0975 9018(Online); 0976-2221 (Print).
- Sunil Kumar Jangir, Naveen Hemrajani, "Survey of Security Threats and Counter Measures in Mobile Ad-Hoc Networks" Published in Volume 6, Issue12, December 2015 Edition. in International Journal of Scientific and Engineering Research IJSER.

International Conference:

- Sunil kumar Jangir¹, Naveen Hemrajani². "**Investigation of MANET Routing Protocols via Quantitative Metrics**" Proceedings of ISDB-ACM-WIR 2018 by Springer.
- Sunil kumar Jangir, Naveen Hemrajani, "A Detection Technique for Overhead Minimization in Tunneling Attack" Proceedings of International Conference on Recent Advancement on Computer and Communication by Springer Nature Singapore 2018,pp. 655-644, ISBN 978-981-10-8198-9, 2017.
- Sunil kumar Jangir¹, Naveen Hemrajani², "Multimedia Traffic over MANETs: Evaluation and Performance Analysis" Fourth International Conference on Networks & Communications (NETCOM-2012) held in Chennai, India on December 22 24, 2012 published by Springer in Lecture Notes in Electrical Engineering (LNEE) series.
- Sunil Kumar Jangir¹, Ritu Gupta², Chandra Prakash Sharma³, Ruchi Dave⁴ "Estimating Cost Benefit by Improving Software through Re-Engineering" Published in proceeding for RTCMC-2012 by OITM, Hisar. SPONSORED by AICTE. ISBN No. 978-81-923446-0-7, Volume-1 ,Page no.224. Date on 25-26th Feb. 2012.
- Sunil kumar Jangir¹, Naveen Hemrajani², "A Comprehensive Review on Detection of Wormhole Attack in MANET". in IEEE ICTBIG 2016: 2016 International Conference on ICT in Business, Industry, and Government (ICTBIG) published at IEEE Xplore Digital Library on 18-19 November 2016 at Indore. ISBN: 978-1-5090-5515-9, https://doi.org/10.1109/ICTBIG.2016.7892688, 2016
- Sunil kumar Jangir¹ ,Naveen Hemrajani², "Evaluation of Black hole, Wormhole and Sybil Attacks in Mobile Ad-hoc Networks". 2nd International Conference on Information and Communication Technology for Competitive Strategies" (ICTCS 2016) published at ACM Digital Library on 4-5 March 2016 at Udaipur. ISBN: 978-1-4503-3962-9, https://doi.org/10.1145/2905055.2905133, 2016

Session chaired

- Chaired a Session at 4th International Conference on Information and Communication Technology for Competitive Strategies (ICTCS-2019) organized by the BHUPAL NOBLES UNIVERSITY, UDAIPUR, India, held on December 13th, 2019.
- Chaired a Session at *International Conference of Information Management (ICIMMI-2019)* under the scheme TEQIP-III (RTU-ATU) organized by Poornima Institute of Engineering & Technology, Jaipur on 15, December 2019.
- Chaired a Session at 1st FICR International Conference of Rising Threats in Expert Applications & Solutions, 2020 organized by the Department of Computer Science & Information Technology at IIS (deemed to be University), Jaipur (INDIA), held on January 19th, 2020.
- Chaired a Session at 5th International Conference on Advanced Machine Learning Technologies and Applications (AMLTA-2020) was organized by the Manipal University, Jaipur, on February 13th -15th ,2020

CONFERENCES/WORKSHOPS/ TRAINING PROGRAMS ATTENDED

- Attended a 5 Days FDP on Robotic Process Automation by UI-Path at Bennett University, Noida in May 2019.
- Attended a 5 Days FDP on Entrepreneurship Skills by MNIT Jaipur in March 2019.
- Attended a 2 Days workshop on Incubator Manager Training by Nexus, Delhi in Feb 2019.
- Attended a 3 Days workshop on OBE Process by NBA, Delhi in 2018.
- Attended a 3 Days FDP Program on Deep Learning at Bennett University, Nodia in 2018.
- Attended a 5 Days FDP Program on Machine Learning & Python at SKIT, Jaipur in 2018.
- Attended a 3 Days FDP Program on LaTeX at GIT, Jaipur in 2018.
- Attended a 2 days FDP Program on MOOCs & Digital Contents Development at Anand College, Jaipur in 2018.
- Attended a 5 Days FDP Program on Advanced Wireless Networks at MNIT, Jaipur in 2014.
- Attended a 7 Days workshop on Teaching Skills Aarambh conducted by Wipro in 2012.
- Attended two day National Workshop on "Research Methodology and Scientific Writings" supported by DST at JECRC on February 28-29, 2012.
- Certified for successfully completion of a four day training program on "Object Oriented Analysis and Design using UML with essentials of Rational Software Architect" conducted by IBM from 27th to 30th September 2011.
- Attended National Workshop on "Wireless Networks: Today & Beyond" at SGVU, Jaipur sponsored by CSI on September 20, 2010.
- Attended FDP Program Conducted by TCS on Risk Management at Poornima Engineering College. Jaipur.
- Attended FDP Program Conducted by EMC² on Storage & Information Management system at Jaipur Engineering College & Research Center, Jaipur.
- Attended 4 day workshop on IBM RFT tool conducted by IBM at JECRC in June 2010.
- Attended 4 day workshop on IBM RAD v6.0 tool conducted by IBM at JECRC in March 2010.
- Attended 3 day workshop on IBM DB2 9 Fundamentals conducted by IBM at JECRC in February 2010.

Ph.D. Thesis

Attacks over Mobile Ad-hoc Networks: Challenges, Detection and Counter Measures Purpose:

To develop light weight, non-cryptographic based detection methods and countermeasures against attacks in reactive routing protocols of MANETs.

Tool: ns3

M.TECH. DISSERTATION WORK

QOS Provisioning for transmitting Delay Sensitive application over MANET using Call Admission Control (CAC)

Purpose:

To discover route from source to destination that will satisfy the application delay requirement with minimum overhead and perform efficient admission control.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Entitled 55th rank in Rajasthan Board in 10th standard, for which rewarded with scholarship.
- Achieved "BEST STUDENT" award from Bharat Vikas Parishad.
- Got "Best project award" in 2009 in IT department (Project: Multi-Touch Detection System).
- Secured I Rank in M.Tech.(Software Engineering) II, III & IV semester Examination at Suresh GyanVihar University, Jaipur.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Date of Birth: Oct-09-1987
Passport no.: **H4676408**

REFRENCES

Dr. Naveen hemrajani

Head of Department (CSE) School of Engineering & Technology, JECRC University, Jaipur Email:naven_h@yahoo.com

Dr. Chaagan Choudhary

Postdoc Fellow University of Padua

Email: chhagan.iiita@gmail.com

Dr. Garima Mathur

Head of Department (E&C) PCE, Sitapura, Jaipur

Email: garimamathurjec@gmail.com

Place:	
Date:	(Dr. Sunil Kumar Jangir)

Responsibilities at Mody University Science & Technology (MUST): (June 2019 – Till Date)

- Faculty In-charge Student Chapter of "IEEE" at MUST, in July 2019.
- Faculty In-charge Co-Cubes assessment for SET in MUST.(July 2019-Till)
- Co-coordinator for CSI-National Student convention coding event Feb 2020.
- SPOC for Smart India Hackathon at MUST, Jan. 2020.

Responsibilities at JECRC Foundation: (Nov. 2019 – June 2019)

INITIATIVE

- Initiated the Student Chapter of "ACM" at JECRC, Jaipur in Jan 2019.
- SPOC for Smart India Hackathon at JECRC, Jaipur March 2019.
- Convener JECRC HACKATHON 1.0 at JECRC, Jaipur Jan 2017.
- Initiated IT Hackathon and Conducted 2 Sessions Successfully in Department of IT-JECRC August 2017-2018.
- Initiated IT IDEATHON and Conducted 2 Sessions Successfully in Department of IT-JECRC November 2017-2018..
- Initiated SIP Expo and Conducted 2 Sessions Successfully in Department of IT-JECRC September 2017-2018.
- Initiated the Student Chapter of "Computer Society of India" at JECRC, Jaipuin Jan 2012.
- Co-SPOC for IBM Initiative Program at JECRC, Jaipur Jan 2010-2013.

CONFERENCE CONVENER

- Convener International Conference on Information Technology & Digital Application ICITDA-2019.
- Convener National Conference on Information Technology & Security Application NCITSA-2019.
- Convener International Conference on Information Technology & Digital Application ICITDA-2018.

WORKSHOP/SEMINAR COORDINATED

- Organizing Team member of "RESEARCH MEHODOLOGY AND SCIENTIFIC WRITINGS" Supported by DST Rajasthan in February 28-29,2012 held at JECRC, Jaipur
- Faculty development Program Conducted by **TCS** on "Cloud Computing" in April 2011 at JECRC, Jaipur.
- Faculty development Program Conducted by **EMC**² on "**Storage & Information Management system**" in February 2011 at JECRC, Jaipur.
- International Conference on "Web Based Learning and Library Management "supported by CSIR in January 30-31, 2011 at JECRC, Jaipur.
- Workshop on "**Open Source Technology and their Uses**" at JECRC Foundation (JECRC & UDML). in March 2010
- Workshop on "Ajax Uses In .NET Framework" supported by Keyprompt Technology Pvt. Ltd. Jaipur, at JECRC Foundation (JECRC & UDML). In April 2010.
- Workshop on "TGMC 2010" conducted by IBM at JECRC in December 2009.

TRAINING PROGRAMS COORDINATED

- Coordinated the training program on IBM Tools i.e. DB2, RAD, RFT conducted by Authorized Training Partners of IBM.
- Organized 45 days training program on ".Net technology" within the campus, conducted by Key prompt Technologies Pvt. Ltd. in July2010
- Organized 90 days training program on "Networking applies with Routers and switches" within the campus, conducted by RNS InfoTech. Pvt. Ltd. in November 2010

TRAINING AND PLACEMENT OFFICER-Departmental (DEC-2009 to OCT-2011)

- Core Team Member for **TCS** 2011 recruitment drive, a history was created **239** got placed in TCS from **JECRC Foundation** in December 24-26, 2010.
- Core Team Member for TCS 2012 recruitment drive, a history was created 267 got placed in
- TCS from **JECRC Foundation** in **S**eptember 20-22, 2011.

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITY COORDINATOR

- Published monthly News Letter "IT-NewsLetter" from Jan 2017-Jun 2019.
- Published magazine "The-Edifier" From July 2014-June 2019.
- Core team Member of "DST WOS-A" Interviews held at JECRC from 7th-8th Feb.2012.
- Core team member of "i-Weekend 2012", an International level technical fest held at JECRC From 3th-5thFeb. 2012.
- Organized 5 day tour for students of I.T. Department at Rishikesh, Mussoorie from 12th -16th Oct 2010
- Core team member of "Renaissance 2010-till", a national level technical cum cultural fest held at JECRC every year.
- Core team member of Anti Ragging team of JECRC foundation.
- Core team member of RPET Counseling in year 2012,2013.
- Editor Member of The Edifier Departmental Magazine from January 2012.

Place:	
Date:	(Dr. Sunil Kumar Jangir)